♪When sorrow and joy blend into ink♪
♪عندما يمتزج الحزن والفرح في الحبر♪
♪Flowers fade, rain falls, helpless as time♪
تذبل الأزهار، ويهطل المطر، عاجزين كعجز الزمن.
♪Lament this frail body, tangled in love and hate♪
♪رثوا هذا الجسد الهزيل، المتشابك بين الحب والكراهية♪
♪Yet I still wrestle with fate♪
♪ومع ذلك ما زلتُ أصارع القدر♪
♪Snow drifts down, burying all glory♪
♪ يتساقط الثلج، فيدفن كل مجد ♪
♪Blame this destiny granted to me♪
♪ألوم هذا القدر الذي مُنح لي♪
♪Trapped in the chains of love and cause♪
♪محاصرون في قيود الحب والقضية♪
♪When the dust finally settles♪
♪عندما تهدأ الأمور أخيرًا♪
=Glory in Shadows=
=المجد في الظلال=
=Episode 1= (Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org)
=الحلقة 1= (ادعموا المشرفين، شاهدوا الحلقة على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org)
(Prefecture Governor's Manor)
(مقر حاكم المحافظة)
(Xie Siyun Concubine of Shen Family)
(شيه سيون محظية عائلة شين)
After all this fuss,
بعد كل هذه الضجة،
Madam must be starving.
لا بد أن السيدة تتضور جوعاً.
Bring her something nice to eat!
أحضر لها شيئاً لذيذاً لتأكله!
(Shen Yaochu Eldest Daughter of Shen Family)
(شين ياوتشو، الابنة الكبرى لعائلة شين)
Come at me instead!
تعال إليّ بدلاً من ذلك!
Don't touch my mother!
لا تلمس أمي!
Xie Siyun.
شيه سيون.
Even if my mom dies,
حتى لو ماتت أمي،
my father will marry someone else.
سيتزوج والدي من امرأة أخرى.
You'll never become the rightful wife!
لن تصبحي الزوجة الشرعية أبداً!
Ah, I almost forgot.
آه، كدت أنسى.
You mustn't get hurt.
يجب ألا تتأذى.
You still have to be married off.
لا يزال يتعين عليك الزواج.
Nanny Liu.
المربية ليو.
Mother!
الأم!
Stop!
قف!
Eat it!
كُلْه!
Mother!
الأم!
Eat it now!
تناوله الآن!
(Shen Yunxi Second daughter of Shen Family)
(الابنة الثانية لشين يونشي من عائلة شين)
Eat it.
تناوله.
Will you marry him or not?
هل ستتزوجينه أم لا؟
I will...
أنا سوف...
See, if you had
انظر، لو كان لديك
(Shen Yaochu's Birth Mother) said that earlie,
قالت (والدة شين ياوتشو البيولوجية) في وقت سابق،
your mother wouldn't have to suffer.
لن تضطر والدتك للمعاناة.
General Li achieved great merit.
حقق الجنرال لي إنجازات عظيمة.
Marrying him as the rightful wife
الزواج منه كزوجة شرعية
is the greatest blessing for you.
إنها أعظم نعمة لك.
But he's already dead.
لكنه ميت بالفعل.
You simply wish
أنت ببساطة تتمنى
to send me to the grave after him.
ليرسلني إلى القبر بعده.
Refuse the marriage,
ارفض الزواج،
and she will be the one who dies.
وستكون هي التي ستموت.
Xie Siyun.
شيه سيون.
You've done every wicked deed...
لقد ارتكبت كل عمل شرير...
Aren't you afraid of karma?
ألا تخاف من الكارما؟
Karma?
كارما؟
There's only one rule in this world.
لا توجد سوى قاعدة واحدة في هذا العالم.
Either your hand is on my throat,
إما أن يدك على حلقي،
or mine is on yours.
أو أن خاصتي موجودة على خاصتك.
Don't blame me for playing dirty,
لا تلومني على اللعب بطريقة غير نزيهة،
but your own fragile neck.
لكن رقبتك الهشة هي الأخرى.
The auspicious hour is near.
اقتربت الساعة الميمونة.
Prepare the young lady's attire.
جهزي ملابس الفتاة الصغيرة.
Xie Siyun.
شيه سيون.
If anything happens to my mother,
إذا حدث أي مكروه لأمي،
I will never let you off the hook!
لن أتركك تفلت من العقاب أبداً!
Mother.
الأم.
Father doesn't know about this yet.
الأب لا يعلم بهذا الأمر بعد.
That's the point, we must send
هذا هو المغزى، يجب أن نرسل
that vixen away while he's away.
تلك المرأة الماكرة تبتعد عنه أثناء غيابه.
But no need to be so tense.
لكن لا داعي لكل هذا التوتر.
When has he ever cared for them?
متى اهتم بهم؟
True enough.
صحيح.
But if Shen Yaochu seizes power
لكن إذا استولى شين ياوتشو على السلطة
in the Li family,
في عائلة لي،
-Power? -We...
-القوة؟ -نحن...
Do you think that girl
هل تعتقد أن تلك الفتاة
can survive tonight?
هل يستطيع النجاة الليلة؟
(Joyful)
(مبهج)
Midnight approaches.
يقترب منتصف الليل.
Today, the Guardian General
اليوم، الحارس العام
Li Jingchuan, son of the Marquis of Anding,
لي جينغتشوان، ابن ماركيز أندينغ،
returns in spirit
يعود بالروح
to wed Shen Yaochu, the Prefecture Governor's eldest daughter.
للزواج من شين ياوتشو، الابنة الكبرى لحاكم المحافظة.
(Harmony Brings Auspiciousness)
(الانسجام يجلب الحظ السعيد)
Though the wedding is at midnight,
على الرغم من أن حفل الزفاف سيقام في منتصف الليل،
I haven't treated you unfairly.
لم أعاملك بظلم.
Look at your crown and bridal robe.
انظري إلى تاجكِ ورداء زفافكِ.
Send my mom to Guanyin Nunnery,
أرسلوا أمي إلى دير غوانيين،
and I'll marry him.
وسأتزوجه.
If you cross the Li family,
إذا تقاطعت مع عائلة لي،
my father won't be lenient.
لن يكون والدي متساهلاً.
Fine.
بخير.
I'll send her there tomorrow.
سأرسلها إلى هناك غداً.
Right now.
الآن.
At a time like this,
في مثل هذا الوقت،
you're still bargaining with me?
هل ما زلت تتفاوض معي؟
It's exactly because of the timing
يرجع ذلك تحديداً إلى التوقيت
that you have no time to think
أنه ليس لديك وقت للتفكير
of a countermeasure, right?
كإجراء مضاد، أليس كذلك؟
Lady Siyun,
السيدة سيون،
the auspicious hour is near.
الساعة الميمونة قريبة.
The Li family's wedding procession
موكب زفاف عائلة لي
is arriving as well.
سيصل أيضاً.
The couple bound in fate shall stand together.
سيقف الزوجان اللذان جمعهما القدر معاً.
May this life be lived without regrets.
أتمنى أن تُعاش هذه الحياة بلا ندم.
May their souls rest together in peace.
رحمهم الله وأسكنهم فسيح جناته.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
I'll send her off right now.
سأرسلها الآن.
I need to see my mom leave.
أريد أن أرى أمي تغادر.
Shen Yaochu,
شين ياوتشو,
do not harbor thoughts you shouldn't.
لا تُضمر أفكاراً لا ينبغي لك أن تُضمرها.
You know what I mean.
أنت تعرف ما أعنيه.
Even if I spare her life,
حتى لو أبقيت على حياتها،
I can make her wish she weren't alive.
بإمكاني أن أجعلها تتمنى لو لم تكن على قيد الحياة.
Stop wasting time.
توقف عن إضاعة الوقت.
The time is near.
لقد اقترب الوقت.
I wish you and General Li
أتمنى لك وللجنرال لي كل التوفيق
a harmonious union.
اتحاد متناغم.
And a swift reunion.
ولم شمل سريع.
Lady Siyun,
السيدة سيون،
you want me buried with him?
هل تريدني أن أدفن معه؟
Then why don't we die together?
فلماذا لا نموت معاً؟
Madam!
سيدتي!
Mother!
الأم!
Guards! Guards!
حراس! حراس!
A murderer!
قاتل!
(Prefecture Governor's Manor)
(مقر حاكم المحافظة)
I'm Shen Yaochu, widow of General Li.
أنا شين ياوتشو، أرملة الجنرال لي.
Lady Siyun is stopping me.
السيدة سيون توقفني.
General, please help me!
أيها الجنرال، أرجوك ساعدني!
-Shen Yaochu! - Mother...
-شين ياوتشو! - أمي...
When have I ever stopped you?
متى منعتك من قبل؟
Thank you, General.
شكراً لك يا جنرال.
And you are...?
وأنت؟
I am Xu Shan, Deputy General under General Li.
أنا شو شان، نائب الجنرال لي.
Deputy General Xu.
نائب الجنرال شو.
Lady Siyun is stopping me.
السيدة سيون توقفني.
She wants me to marry other.
إنها تريدني أن أتزوج غيرك.
I risked my life to escape.
لقد خاطرت بحياتي للهروب.
Please, General, take me away from here.
أرجوك يا جنرال، خذني من هنا.
I never stopped you!
لم أمنعك أبداً!
It was clearly you!
كان ذلك واضحاً، أنت!
How come you're so devoted
كيف أصبحتَ مخلصاً إلى هذا الحد؟
to General Li?
إلى الجنرال لي؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Years ago, I had the honor of meeting him.
قبل سنوات، تشرفت بلقائه.
Since then, he's never left my thoughts.
منذ ذلك الحين، لم يغب عن بالي أبداً.
General Li sacrificed himself.
ضحى الجنرال لي بنفسه.
I've admired him deeply.
لقد كنت معجباً به بشدة.
Even though he's gone,
رغم رحيله،
I'd still marry his memorial
سأتزوج نصبه التذكاري
tablet willingly.
الجهاز اللوحي عن طيب خاطر.
You've met him?
هل قابلته؟
Of course I have.
بالطبع فعلت.
Shen Yaochu,
شين ياوتشو,
you're slandering me!
أنت تشوه سمعتي!
It was you who schemed to harm me!
أنت من دبر المكيدة لإيذائي!
So now, will you let me marry or not?
والآن، هل ستسمح لي بالزواج أم لا؟
Of course, the marriage shall proceed.
بالطبع، سيتم الزواج.
Take me away.
خذني بعيداً.
It looks like rain.
يبدو أن الجو سيمطر.
Then please, Madam,
إذن تفضلي يا سيدتي،
step into the sedan.
ادخل إلى السيارة السيدان.
The auspicious hour has come!
لقد حانت الساعة الميمونة!
Madam, please step into the sedan chair.
سيدتي، تفضلي بالجلوس في المحفة.
(Prefecture Governor's Manor)
(مقر حاكم المحافظة)
(When I reach the Li Manor,)
(عندما أصل إلى قصر لي،)
(Late Guardian General Li Jingchuan) (I might be buried alongside General Li.)
(الجنرال لي جينغتشوان، الحارس الراحل) (ربما سأدفن بجانب الجنرال لي.)
(Now,)
(الآن،)
(I still don't know if Mother is safe.)
(ما زلت لا أعرف ما إذا كانت أمي بخير.)
(I cannot die.)
(لا يمكنني أن أموت.)
(If Lady Siyun takes this chance to harm her,)
(إذا انتهزت السيدة سيون هذه الفرصة لإيذائها،)
(all my efforts today would be in vain.)
(كل جهودي اليوم ستكون عبثاً.)
(I must live.)
(يجب أن أعيش.)
Deputy General Xu.
نائب الجنرال شو.
What is it, Madam?
ما الأمر يا سيدتي؟
Please come closer for a word.
تفضل بالاقتراب قليلاً لتبادل الحديث.
Madam?
سيدتي؟
It's my old ailment.
إنه مرضي القديم.
I need the master at Guanyin Nunnery to treat me.
أحتاج إلى أن يعالجني المعلم في دير غوانيين.
Please, change our route and take me there first.
من فضلك، غيّر مسارنا واصطحبني إلى هناك أولاً.
I'll summon a physician here instead.
سأستدعي طبيباً إلى هنا بدلاً من ذلك.
Madam, please wait just a moment.
سيدتي، من فضلك انتظري لحظة.
Madam, what is this for?
سيدتي، ما الغرض من هذا؟
Change the course to Guanyin Nunnery.
غيّر المسار إلى دير غوانيين.
Why go there?
لماذا الذهاب إلى هناك؟
I have my own reasons I cannot avoid.
لدي أسبابي الخاصة التي لا يمكنني تجنبها.
You're bold indeed.
أنت جريء حقاً.
What I've done today,
ما فعلته اليوم،
you've seen it all clearly.
لقد رأيت كل شيء بوضوح.
So I won't need to hide.
لذلك لن أحتاج إلى الاختباء.
It's not Lady Siyun who was stopping your marriage,
لم تكن السيدة سيون هي من كانت تمنع زواجك،
but you didn't wish to wed.
لكنك لم ترغب في الزواج.
Change the course.
غيّر المسار.
Head to Guanyin Nunnery.
توجه إلى دير غوانيين.
Now that's interesting.
هذا مثير للاهتمام.
I've made arrangements at the nunnery.
لقد رتبت الأمور في الدير.
Tonight,
الليلة،
be the bride you're meant to be.
كوني العروس التي خُلقتِ لتكوني.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
♪New snow falls thick beneath the eaves♪
♪يتساقط الثلج الجديد بكثافة تحت حواف السقف♪
♪Covering the courtyard gate♪
♪تغطية بوابة الفناء♪
♪Your gaze melts winter into spring♪
♪نظرتك تذيب الشتاء في الربيع♪
♪Turning back from the boundless multitude♪
♪العودة من بين الجموع التي لا حدود لها♪
♪Gazing at you in that fleeting moment♪
♪أنظر إليك في تلك اللحظة العابرة♪
♪All the hardships fade into drifting dust♪
♪تتلاشى كل المصاعب في غبار متناثر♪
♪A foolish dream turns earnest with you in it♪
♪حلمٌ ساذجٌ يتحول إلى حلمٍ جادٍّ بوجودك فيه♪
♪Even a feigned play can grow into true affection♪
♪حتى التمثيل المصطنع يمكن أن يتحول إلى عاطفة حقيقية♪
♪Too many dusks walked alone beneath my umbrella♪
♪كثير من الغسقات سارت وحيدة تحت مظلتي♪
♪Yet I crave the warmth left in your embrace♪
♪لكنني أتوق إلى الدفء المتبقي في حضنك♪
♪Among thousands of bright lamps, is there one♪
♪من بين آلاف المصابيح الساطعة، هل يوجد واحد؟♪
♪That waits quietly for me?♪
♪هل ينتظرني بصمت؟♪
♪Time grinds through the rings of memory♪
♪ يمر الوقت سريعاً عبر حلقات الذاكرة ♪
♪Only you keep me warm in the long night♪
♪أنتِ وحدكِ من تُدفئينني في الليل الطويل♪
♪Scars left by the days gone by♪
♪ندوبٌ خلّفتها الأيام الخوالي♪
♪Lie upon the lines of our hands together♪
♪استلقوا على خطوط أيدينا معًا♪
♪I hold out a heart sincere and true♪
♪أُخرج قلباً صادقاً وحقيقياً♪
♪Crossing the deep courtyard♪
♪عبور الفناء العميق♪
♪Just to trade it for one kiss from you♪
♪فقط لأستبدلها بقبلة واحدة منك♪
♪Praying our hair turns gray without regret♪
♪ندعو أن يتحول شعرنا إلى اللون الرمادي دون ندم♪
♪So that true love will finally come to be♪
♪حتى يتحقق الحب الحقيقي في النهاية♪